I have put this program in place for a reason and that is to better protect the American
people.
And when we find somebody who may have information regarding a potential attack on America, you
bet we're going to detain them.
And you bet we're going to question them because the American people expect us to
find out information, actionable intelligence, so we can help them, help protect them.
That's our job.
So that was archived footage from the Oval Office of former President Bush referring to two
secret memos in 2005 that authorized extreme interrogation tactics against terrorist suspects.
As you can see, U.S. policy has been evolving to where we are for quite some time.
Hello and welcome to Colonial Outcast, the anti-imperialist podcast that your problematic
uncle who still believes that the global war on terror was done for all the right reasons
will hate.
I also just landed in LA two hours ago and my webcam is busted.
The audio is crazy and the internet might cut out.
So apologies for the trash quality of my video.
Look, we aren't shadow banned on audio platforms, but we are getting massively suppressed on
YouTube and we'll probably eventually get deplatformed.
So you can join our Patreon as a free member if that happens and still get access
to all regular video episodes for free.
Anyways, Mint Press News is going to be cutting segments from this interview to post on their
own platform because we have got a very special guest this week and we're just going to jump
right in.
So today we are joined by John Kiriakou, CIA whistleblower and former intelligence
analyst and operations officer for the CIA's Counterterrorism Center.
He was integral in exposing the CIA's enhanced interrogation program in 2007 and did some
time for it.
I believe he is now an author, books linked in the description and host of CIA declassified
season two, which is now streaming on Unifid TV.
I'm going to clarify the pronunciation of that in a second, also in the description.
You have a busy schedule, so thank you so much for coming on.
Here's your, my pleasure.
And is this UNFYD TV or UNIFYD unified?
Yeah.
Oh my, I don't know how I missed that.
That's okay.
Everybody does.
It's been a long week unified.
I don't know.
I just went back to like some stupid like military jargon term, how I would pronounce
it like Unifid.
Wow.
Totally missed that one.
No worries.
So anyways, for the audience, a rough outline, the legacy of the Iraq war, U.S.
relation and whistleblowing, U.S. Israel relations and the current internal administration
drama about the Iran nuclear deal, which has been a drama, well, since the revolution.
Yes.
And the expansion of the Guantanamo Bay and Seacott Prison in El Salvador.
As the kids say, it's giving extraordinary rendition from the global war on terror.
So again, let's just get right into it.
And I personally want to start off with this question because I spent the most form
of years of my life in Joint Special Operations Command in the 75th Ranger
Regiment.
And when I started to branch more into like human intelligence collection and got plugged
into the kinetic strike targeting cycle of drone strikes in Afghanistan officially.
Of course, I knew we were dropping people who shouldn't have been dropped.
And I was a field interrogator for a while and we knew other interrogators that were
still like pretty brutal.
I never believed in negative incentives.
It's just not who I was personally, you know, and there were some reforms after
the torture report came out, but basically it was basically just don't use
waterboarding or threatened to use dogs and don't get caught.
My question that I always like to ask, like, when you put the wheels in motion
to blow the whistle on human rights abuses by U.S. clandestine services,
why did you do it or what did you hope to achieve and put yourself at such
personal risk?
Like, I've just met so many guys who either didn't care or were resentful
that they couldn't go even further.
So sure.
You know, one of the reasons why I did it was, well, let me back up.
I was the chief of CIA counterterrorism operations in Pakistan in the
immediate aftermath of 9-11.
When I returned to CIA headquarters in May of 2002, I was asked if I wanted
to be trained in what they called the use of enhanced interrogation techniques.
I had never heard that term before.
I didn't know what it meant.
And the way it was explained to me in my mind was clearly torture.
And I was well read enough to know that we have the Federal
Torture Act of 1946.
We have the United Nations Convention against torture.
We have other laws that that very clearly delineate what we are
allowed to do in national security custodial interrogations.
I declined the training.
I was the only one of the 14 people who were approached who declined to be involved.
At the same time, I was promoted because I had led the capture of Abu
Zubaydah, who we believed was the number three in al-Qaeda at the time
and who was the first person to be subject to torture.
So I got promoted to be the executive assistant to the CIA's deputy director
for operations.
And in that position, I was able to see for one year, I was able to see
literally everything that the CIA was doing around the world.
It was 100% crystal clear to me that there were a lot of people inside
the CIA who were opposed to the torture program.
People were writing cables back to headquarters from the secret site
saying, whoa, this is not what I signed up for.
I'm not going to do this.
I want to come home.
That's called a curtailment or you curtail your overseas assignment.
It's a career ending decision to just say, send me home.
I'm not doing this.
There were people who resigned from the secret site.
There were nurses who fainted while watching the torture sessions.
There were doctors from the Office of Medical Services who would write,
wait a minute, wait a minute.
I took an oath to do no harm and you want me to be there to revive
this guy after you kill him so that you can torture him more?
I'm not doing that.
So I thought, well, certainly somebody is going to say something.
After my tour on the executive floor was done, I went to the United
Nations for my final tour and then I resigned from the CIA and I went
into the private sector, still thinking somebody's going to say
something and nobody did.
And then finally in 2007, I said something to ABC News.
My only regret was that I left five and a half years on the table.
I learned about the torture in May of 2002.
It started on August the 2nd, 2002 and I didn't say anything
until December the 11th, 2007.
And I wish I had said something sooner.
Did more than most.
What was the the source of, I don't know, your desire to do that
because I've not known people opposed to the torture program
just for very practical, real, politic reasons.
It doesn't work, right?
It doesn't work.
And if it ever comes out, it degrades U.S. soft power globally.
Yeah, it very much does.
The reason why I felt so strongly about it is as soon as I like the
moment that I heard about it, my response to the senior officer
who approached me was that sounds like a torture program.
Torture is illegal.
And he said, no, it's not a torture program.
The president signed off on it and the Justice Department signed off
on it. It's perfectly legal.
And I said, I don't know, man, let me think about it.
So besides asking a senior officer for his opinion and his opinion
was quite strongly in opposition to the program, I started to do my
own research and what I found was, and this was very convincing to
me, was that in 1945 and 1946, we executed Japanese soldiers
who had waterboarded American POWs.
That was a death penalty crime to waterboard somebody.
And we executed several Japanese soldiers for waterboarding.
On January the 11th, 1968, the Washington Post ran a front page
photograph of an American soldier waterboarding a North Vietnamese
prisoner. The day that that picture was published, the
Secretary of Defense, Robert S. McNamara ordered an
investigation. The soldier was arrested, he was convicted of
torture, and he was sentenced to 20 years at hard labor at
Leavenworth. Besides that, not only is the US a signatory to
the United Nations Convention Against Torture.
It's the author of the United Nations Convention Against
Torture. So if waterboarding somebody was a death penalty
offense or worthy of 20 years at hard labor, and not only did we
feel so strongly about the law here in the United States, but
we made it international law by writing the UN Convention. How
could it just magically be be legal in 2002? Just poof by
magic.
Congress never passed any amendment to the law.
Congress never changed the law. We changed. It's like when
Bill Clinton, you know, disagreed with what the what the
definition of is is. You can't just pretend that the law doesn't
exist, or pretend that you somehow have the authority to
ignore it because you don't like it. And so that's why I felt so
strongly about it. And that's why I felt that the American
people had to write had a right to know about it.
Yeah, and decide for themselves. You know, I think we've
kind of seen the disintegration of any any pretense that any sort
of law of land warfare or international law really exists when
it comes to the United States. I mean, one of the most telling
things about like selling the saying the quiet part out loud
was when the head prosecutor of the ICC was told, and he went
on record saying that he was approached by a Western
official saying that the ICC was for warlords in Africa and
thugs like Putin. And that kind of definitely sums it up. And
now, what we've seen and what I've always been frustrated
about is like American voters generally only care about
domestic issues and not really foreign policy because, you know,
geopolitics is difficult. A lot of people weren't educated and
that kind of stuff. But when we break laws overseas, and this
is just like, longstanding collodial theory, whatever
laws we break overseas and the colonies boomerangs back
towards like the Imperial Corps, or whatever you want to call
it. So now we're seeing that. And I think a good tie in I was
going to talk about this at the end. But another thing that was
started under the Clinton administration, I believe was, and
I'm seeing kind of like a corollary with the ICE
detentions and the constitutional crisis of the Supreme
Court, a federal judge is saying turn the planes around and
the White House is like, we're not turning the planes
around. We're going to get them out of the country so fast
that you can't stop us. And then once they're out of the
country, they're gone because it's basically easier to take
people away from the law than take the law away from people.
And this reminds me of extraordinary rendition.
You know, this really is the definition of an
extraordinary rendition. Well, I'll let you decide, it
could be just a rendition. Either way, it's illegal.
There's no due process here, right? This this guy in from
Maryland that has been said to El Salvador was not given due
process. He's never been charged with a crime. He's
never been even accused of a crime. And it's funny, if you
look at the at the Washington Post at the New York Times, CNN,
MSNBC, they say, Oh my God, there's this guy in Maryland
and he was scooped up and he was sent to El Salvador. If
you look at Fox or the New York Post or even the Wall
Street Journal, they talk about MS 13 gangbanger sent to
prison in in El Salvador. Well, the fact of the matter is that
he was essentially kidnapped and sent to El Salvador. That's
what a rendition is. So you know, let's call the spade a
spade here. The guy was rendered to El Salvador. And
another thing that's funny to me is, you know, you see
these clips from the Oval Office of, of, you know,
Trump reading the riot act, you know, to, to Lodomers
Zelensky, or to other world leaders. And then he just
cowers in the face of the power and the authority of the
president of El Salvador. It doesn't make any sense to me.
And not only that, you know, the president of El Salvador
gives the middle finger to everybody and says, No, we're
not going to let him go. And we're not letting Senator
Chris Van Hollen meet with him. And we're not letting
Van Hollen take him home. And, and nobody's going to meet
with him. And he's not going to be released. And then we have
the president say, actually, we would like to finance the
building of four or five more of these 30,000 unit, you
know, super prisons. Well, what the heck is that? So is the
plan that we just are doing away with, with due process?
Do Americans or US persons, people who have valid
green cards, do they just no longer have civil rights and
civil liberties? Because it sure looks like that's the road
we're taking.
As someone with a background in intelligence, you know, who's
gone after high value targets like yourself. It doesn't seem
because they're choosing guys 75% of whom it seems like
do not have critical criminal records or even like gang
tattoos. So it seems from an outsider that these they're
picking these battles because there are illegal immigrants who
are criminals who they have committed crimes. But they're
not going after them. They're going after these guys who have
legal protections that are very sympathetic figures like
working father. It looks to me as someone who, you know, did
that kind of like, like night raids for five years. It
looks like they don't have the intelligence architecture or
collection to actually have any of these guys.
You are absolutely right. You are absolutely right. If they had
the intelligence, they would get the guys that Donald Trump
famously called in 2016 the bad hombres scoop them up, not the
restaurant tour who's married to an American woman in
Indianapolis and has run a successful steakhouse for 30
years. Why are you throwing him out? Or the 19 year old kid
from Venezuela who the agent says like, I don't think this is
him and then a superior said take him anyways.
Yeah, exactly. Or the kid in Vermont where they come and say,
Hey, come to the INS office in Vermont, you could take your
citizenship test. And they've got masks and hoods and and
camo uniforms, and they scoop them up and put them on a plane
and throw them out. Or the Turkish PhD candidate, whose only
crime is that she wrote an op-ed critical of Israel's
treatment of Palestinians. But instead of crime, I just don't
understand what the point is, other than to squelch
dissent, show unflinching support for Israeli war crimes,
and and try to exhibit this fake toughness.
I wanted to to that end, I kind of wanted to ask you about the
deployment of of the word terrorist. Yeah. And because I
don't have any experience like even like looking at like the
cartels from an intelligence perspective. They have kind of
used we're kind of seeing a fusing of two avenues of
approach, in my opinion, we see the deployment of the word
terrorist, terrorist sympathizers about the pro Palestine
stuff. You know, there we're supporting a, you know, either
because people think it's a national liberation movement. You
know, you're hit with the word terrorist. And of course, that's
been normalized through over the past 20 odd years. But now
we're seeing like Pam Bondi, the Attorney General of the
United States call these gang members foreign terrorists and
they've designated certain cartels in Mexico, foreign terrorist
organizations. How do you see that like, so it seems like
they're using the mechanism of deportation along with the
deployment of like the pro Palestine movement to like meld it
all together into this anti dissent apparatus. And I was
just wondering, like, what strikes you as significant as
like naming gangs as terrorist organizations? And like, what
consequences that could have going forward?
There was a very bureaucratic reason to do that, which I'll
get into in just a second. But you know, there's a, there's
quite a simple definition of terrorism that we used to use
at the CIA. And it was, it was any, any action in support of
political change that uses violence to terrorize a civilian
population. Very simple. So Carlos, the jackal is a terrorist.
But you know, some national liberation movement that does not
target civilians isn't is not a terrorist group. Now, the
reason why Donald Trump and the State Department used the
terrorism designation on the drug cartels, it was purely
bureaucratic, because then it allows the CIA to budget money
in order to help in this fight against the cartels. It also
gives them legal authorities to use drones against the cartels.
So just a week or two weeks after Trump announced this
change, Rubio Marco Rubio, the Secretary of State was asked if
the CIA would be using drones in the fight against the cartels.
And he said flat out, no. So why bother making the
designation? It was just to allow the transfer of money
from the CIA to other operational entities to use in the in
this fight against the cartels. When I was at the CIA, coming in
speaking Spanish was pretty much a career ender, unless you
wanted to do political issues on the ground in Latin America. Okay,
if you join the directorate of operations, you speak Spanish
and you want to spend your career, you know, in a half a
dozen countries around Latin America. Okay, good on you. If
you had any interest at all in drugs, it was a career ender.
Because nobody gives a shit about drugs at the CIA. I'm sure
you've seen the show Narcos on on Netflix. And just as they're
going in to grab, you know, Pablo Escobar or the gentleman of
Cali or whomever, the CIA station chief moves in and just
screws up the whole operation. Well, that was true. And
it's because the CIA never cared about drugs. They cared about
communism back at that time. They cared about terrorism a little
bit later. They care about proliferation. They don't care
about drugs. Well, they still don't care about drugs. So
there's not going to be this big move inside the CIA to focus
on the cartels. This was purely a bureaucratic budgetary and
paperwork exercise to allow the free transfer of money.
Yeah. And I would say that I just might get some questions and
the comments like what about the the Contra with Nicaragua, like
creating a slush fund for Iran and stuff like that. But beyond
that you would
kind of proves that kind of proves the point because the
idea was that the CIA allowed the drugs into the United
States. The drugs made their way to Los Angeles and then the
crack epidemic was born. If it were the other way, it would
have been the CIA trying to stop the flow of cocaine from
Central America to Los Angeles.
Yeah. So they're they're kind of a outward facing entity. So
yeah, I thought the whole thing was bureaucratic. But do
you foresee because I try to not be reactionary when it
comes to these things. And I try to not talk people down
because like last summer, people were like freaking out and
asked me a lot of questions about these National Guard
deployments to Syria. And I was like, guys, it's just a
National Guard rotation. Like it was scheduled for a long
time. I don't get worried until I see active duty air for
active duty orders for like the 101st Airborne and a Marine
Expeditionary Force and and a carrier battle group.
Yeah, always watch the carrier battle groups because if we
start redirecting carrier battle groups, we're serious about
going to war.
Right. And so yeah, I do think just just to wrap up the El
Salvador section, I think it's just going to work its way up
to anyone who descends unless there's some sort of check on
it. And I think that's their intention.
I think so too. I think they're going to force the issue
all the way to the Supreme Court. And even then, I'm not
sure that the administration can be trusted to abide by a
Supreme Court ruling. But I agree, you know, normally, when
people are building their empires within government, they
push and push and push the envelope until the courts push
them back. I think that we're seeing that again now, but
maybe at a higher level.
Right, I would say his his first administration had a lot
of overturn in terms of like his inner circle. But it
seems like everyone is like on page in terms of like the
overriding ideology. Yes, there's some, and we're going to
get into Iran now, some conflict with like, Mike Walls,
National Security Advisor and Marco Rubio being Iran Hawks
and then J.D. Vance, as we could see in Signalgate being
way more like, let's actually do a deal, maybe a civilian
nuclear program could be on the table, which is freaking
the hardliners in Israel out. But you said watch this
the carrier battle groups. And of course, there were two,
there were two in the region under the Biden administration,
but they are sending one another a second carrier battle
group, a sensibly into the Persian Gulf that combined with
the massing of air assets and half our fleet of B2 stealth
bombers, nuclear capable, but also capable of dropping 30,000
pound massive ordinance penetrators, presumably for
underground nuclear hard sites, bunker busters. Yep. Yes. But
bigger ones. I think they're, I'm not really sure about the
history, but I think they were developed for like collapsing
caves in Torah Bora. Yeah, that's exactly, that's exactly
Oh, it is. Yeah. Okay. I remember when we were
experimenting with those during the Afghanistan war, we
captured a guy. He had come out of the, he had come out
of the caves in Torah Bora and crossed the border when
we caught him at the border. And he said that the Americans
I'll never forget the word that he used that the Americans
had detonated a hideous bomb. He called it hideous in the
cave. And when he came out, he was the only person who
lived first of all, and blood had squirted out of his
ears. And he never regained his hearing. But that's when
we were trying to develop these, these bunker busters,
presumably for use, you know, later on against underground
Iranian sites.
Yeah, because Israel doesn't have the capabilities to do
that. But we do. So my question is, well, we're seeing a
carrier battle group go a second one, ostensibly to
like isolate Yemen, and maybe do like naval patrol
operations to stop like the supply flow of like avionics
and electronics from Tehran to the Houthis or whatever. But it
is kind of alarming. And there's this internal drama
about the around nuclear deal within the administration
itself. I don't know what's your read, because from my
perspective, and like even hawkish think tanks like the
Saban Institute of foreign relations in the Brookings
Institute said, like, there's not really anything we can do or
achieve militarily. So I don't know what's your read on it?
You know, I'm actually of two minds on this on this issue.
There's the pessimistic analysis and the optimistic
analysis, the pessimistic analysis is that everything you
said is correct. Right? We've got our stealth bombers in
Diego Garcia, we have an enormous Air Force presence
at Al-Rashid Air Base in in Qatar. The fifth lead is
headquartered in Bahrain. We've got two carrier battle
groups. There's one that's not too terribly far away that we
could bring in the event of hostilities. We also learned a
couple of days ago, that Benjamin Netanyahu, when he
met with Trump on Saturday, specifically asked the United
States to attack Iran. Now, Netanyahu has done that in
every meeting with every president since George H. W.
Bush. And he always is told now. But if there's anybody who's
going to go along with that kind of thing, it would be
Donald Trump. So on Saturday, Netanyahu specifically asked,
please bomb Iran. And to his credit, Trump authorized these
talks that took place in Muscat. So on the pessimistic
side, yeah, we're gearing up to go to war. On the optimistic
side, we used to say in the 70s that only Nixon could go to
China. Right? Richard Nixon was the biggest China hawk that
existed in government. He wanted to nuke the Chinese. And
only, you know, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, which are
always like the last ones that want to go to war, held
him back. Right? No, we shouldn't nuke China. And it
turned out he went to China and Mao feted him. And then
Den Xiaoping, the vice premier came here, and we feted him. And
we gave them, you know, a Lincoln Continental and two
buffaloes, and they gave us the pandas. So that's how it all
got started. Only Nixon could go to China. Well, you know
what? Maybe only Trump can go to Iran. And the reason I
say that is because it's been pretty well reported that
Trump is obsessed with winning the Nobel Peace Prize. He was
infuriated that that Obama was given the Nobel Peace Prize
before he ever lifted a finger as president of the United
States and then didn't deserve it because he killed far more
people than George W. Bush ever killed. But maybe Trump
sees maybe Trump is looking back at the first term and
saying, I kind of I kind of squandered it with the North
Koreans. Nothing ever happened there, even though it was very
promising at the beginning. Maybe I can work something out
with the Iranians and he says to himself, I'm on record as
hating the Iranians so much, I killed their most beloved
general as he was landing at the airport in Baghdad on a
peace mission for heaven's sake. Well, I was surprised
that the Iranians agreed to talk to him in Muscat. And
you remember, last week, the White House said that these
negotiations would be direct. Face to face, the Iranians
said, oh, no, they won't. The Omani foreign minister is going
to shuttle between two conference rooms. Well, in
fact, both things were true. The foreign minister did
shuttle between the two conference rooms. And at
the end, both sides met together with a foreign
minister. They shook hands and they agreed to meet
again on Saturday in Rome. Well, this is how fruitful
negotiations begin. Now there have been very serious
changes in the US position. All of a sudden, the US
has lifted its objection to Iranian development of a
delivery system. This has to be panicking the
Israelis, right? Let's say the Iranians have a bomb,
which the CIA says they don't. Even if they had a
bomb, they have no way to deliver it to Israel. They
can't launch it. They don't have the mechanism for it,
but they're beginning to build the mechanism for it.
The US removed their objection to this development.
And number two, it looks like the US is lifting its
objection to the production of enriched uranium to be
used in power generation. You know, the US
position was no nuclear program, period, or we're
going to bomb you into the Stone Age. That's not the
position right now. Donald Trump's position has
changed pretty dramatically. And it seems to me
that this might be the real basis for negotiations.
Yeah, the thing is, though, it seems like he's
very volatile because he's very volatile. That's
that's what scares me. Yeah, because the thing is
like, yes, he wants the Nobel Peace Prize, but I
just I just feel like instinctively like what it's
starting to look like kind of is Obama's JCPOA, which
Trump slashed. Yeah, I just feel like all it will take
is like one of his his advisors to be like, Mr.
President, this looks like Obama's exact deal. Do
you want to like actually complete Obama's legacy? And
then I'll be like, Nope, shut it all down. Yes, it
could be something that simple.
You know, the sad thing too is that the JCPOA was
actually working. It was the same. It was the same
setup that the United Nations had negotiated with
Saddam Hussein, you know, through UN Security
Council Resolution 986, where there were
international inspectors that were allowed to go
to the nuclear sites. The nuclear sites were
sealed with lead seals. And there were CCTV
cameras everywhere. It was the same deal in Iran. And
it was actually working. But Donald Trump hated that
Barack Obama negotiated it. And that's why he pulled
us out. Yeah, I guess only time will tell. Again, I
try not to be reactionary. But you know, another
fleet of B2 bombers was staged out of Australia
to kind of like intimidate, I guess China over the
straight of Taiwan in 2022, also naval assets
removed there. You know, the US does, you know,
yeah, we rattle the sabers a lot.
Yeah, so hopefully it's just that I mean, I am
cautiously hopeful about the nuclear deal too. But in
our last segment before we have to wrap, Israel
seems kind of less and less like our greatest
our greatest ally and more of like, like a
cunning adversary. I was just wondering my own
experience like dealing with or my friend, I never
worked directly with Israeli special operations
forces, but like some of my buddy in the special
forces group, and one of my former squad leaders
who went into Delta Force said they were almost
intolerable to work with. So what was your
experience in the clandestine services?
They were intolerable to work with. Yes. And
you know what? I'll tell you a story just to
give you an idea. I'll tell you two stories.
My very first briefing when I was a brand spanking
new CIA officer, 35 years ago, January,
was for the local Mossad and Shin Bet
representatives. The briefing was on Iraq, and
it included all of the Iraq analysts in the
building, CIA headquarters. We do not brief the
Israelis at CIA headquarters. The Israelis are
not permitted in the building because when they
were permitted in the building, every time they
come, they would give us a gift that invariably
had a bug inside of it and packed with
batteries. And we're like, all right, you guys
can't come here anymore. So we meet, we
meet the Israelis at this offsite location in
northern Virginia. And because I was the
junior most analyst, I went last. So we went
around the conference room table. It was about
like eight or 10 of us, eight of us, I guess it
was, from the most senior analysts to me, the
most junior. And when they got to me, I used
my real name because I was not undercover. So I
said, my name is John Kiriakou, and I'm going
to brief you today on Saddam Hussein and
the Iraqi cabinet. And the Shin Bet guy says,
please spell your name. So I spelled it. And
then he looks up at me over his glasses and he
goes, you are Jewish. And I said, I am not
recruitable. Don't even think about it. He
asked me in front of all my colleagues, I'm
my Jewish, so he can target me for
recruitment. Number one, number two, several
years later, I transferred into a state
department position. It was an honest to God
state department rotation. I became the
the economic officer at the American Embassy in
Manama Bahrain. But there was a married couple
in my office and they went, the wife went
into the same position at the American
Embassy in, well, it was the American
consulate then in Jerusalem. So her husband,
because she was the lead, her husband went
to the University of Tel Aviv to learn
Arabic. Because they were declared like I
was to the Israelis, you know, the station
chief would say, these are my two
officers, you know them, they're CIA.
The wife is on rotation to the state
department. The husband is going to just
study at the university. So they're not
here for anything untoward. Well, they were
invited to a party one night and at the
ambassador's residence. And then when they
got back to Jerusalem, they walked in the
house and saw that all of their living
room furniture had been rearranged. Just
a message from Mossad, we can come in here
anytime we want and we can do whatever we
want. And there's nothing you can do
about it. At Christmas time, they went to a
party at the ambassador's residence. And
when they got home, people had taken
shits in all their toilets, right? They
have three bedrooms, three bathroom
house, and people had taken shits in
each one of their toilets and just
left it there. Again, this nice message
from the Mossad, we know who you are.
There's nothing you can do to stop us.
Finally, at the end of their two-year
tour, they go to a going away party that
the ambassador had for them. They go back
to their house. Somebody had cut the
dog's tail off and then wrapped it in
gauze and medical tape. Like, why would
you do something like that? Why harass
this couple that is doing literally
nothing to you, that is known to you,
has been declared to you. Why would
you fuck with them like that? But
this is what the Israelis do. That's
how they work.
Yeah, I mean, it seems like they have
a cultural obsession with dominance,
obviously.
And so, yeah, even a couple of my
friends were foreign area officers in
the military throughout West Asia.
And one of the classes you go
through, it's like, who does the
most, around globally, who does the
most adversarial collection on US
military officers? It's not Russia.
No, it's not China. Yeah.
No. Israel was right, was raided at
the CIA as critical threat for
counterintelligence. So it was it
was Israel, Russia, China, Cuba and
Iran and North Korea. Those were the
critical threat countries. Yeah, it's
bad, really bad.
Yeah. And of course, the disconnect
between the intelligence services and
the politicians who give a political
talking point must be very grating to
the people who serve in those
institutions. And the funny thing too
is, you know, at the State Department
among foreign service officers, it's
no secret what the Israelis do.
There was no love of the Israelis
inside the State Department. But
you're right, the pressure comes
from the policy community, comes from
Capitol Hill, from the White House
and Capitol Hill at the State
Department, and especially at the CIA,
you don't need to take those political
issues into consideration. But you
you have to carry out the foreign
policy of the United States, whether
you like it or not.
Yeah, it just reminds me just kind of
like wrap this up when I first started
like branching more into like an
intelligence role within my unit,
kind of like my mentor was like, you
know what, despite what they're saying
in Washington or anything like this,
if we pull out, the entire government
will collapse in two weeks. And that
was in 2011. And nothing changed.
But again, I guess we're just going
to keep putting money and resources
into it. So yeah, that was also a
very frustrating foreign policy. But
anyways, thank you so much for
coming on. And you got a heart out.
Yeah. So John Kiriakou, yeah, he's
he's got a new series on a Unify TV
dot com link in descriptions. And
also he's written a number of books
on CIA whistleblowing, etc. Really
appreciate your time. And my
pleasure. Thanks for having me.
All right. And thank you all for
watching. We will be back next
week. Cheers, y'all. Have a good
weekend.